Liz Izhikevich

RESEARCH OVERVIEW

My research brings a data-driven approach to understanding and improving the Internet's performance and security. I build systems that collect data about network, operator, and attacker behaviors. I use quantitative analysis, including rigorous statistics, on the data my systems collect to surface operational challenges and threats.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Computer Science, Stanford University	2018 – 2024
Dissertation: "A Comprehensive and Real-Time View of the Internet Service Ecosystem"Advisor: Zakir Durumeric	
M.S. in Computer Science, Stanford University	2023
M.S. in Computer Science, University of California, San Diego	2017-2018
- Thesis: "Building and Breaking Burst-Parallel Systems"	
– Advisors: Geoff Voelker and George Porter	
B.S. in Computer Science, University of California, San Diego	2014 – 2017
– Minor: Mathematics.	

POSITIONS

- Assistant Professor, Electrical and Computer Engineering, University of California, Los Angeles, July 2024–Present
- Research Intern, Censys, June 2024–Present
- Graduate Research Fellow, Netflix, June 2023-May 2024

Honors and Awards

• EECS Rising Star, International Recognition	2023
• Community Impact Award, Stanford University	2023
• Student Services Award, Stanford University Computer Science Department	2023
• Community Contribution Paper Award, ACM Internet Measurement Conference	2022
• Graduate Research Fellowship, National Science Foundation ("NSF GRFP")	2018
• Graduate Fellowship in Science and Engineering, Stanford University ("Stanford SGF")	2018
• Department Award for Excellence in Teaching, UC San Diego	2018

† indicates mentee, * indicates co-first authorship

Conference Proceedings

- [1] K. Izhikevich[†], G. Voelker, S. Savage, and L. **Izhikevich**, "Using Honeybuckets to Characterize Serverless Storage Scanning in the Wild", in *IEEE European Symposium on Security and Privacy*, 2024.
- [2] L. **Izhikevich**, M. Tran[†], K. Izhikevich[†], G. Akiwate, and Z. Durumeric, "Democratizing LEO Satellite Network Measurement", in *ACM SIGMETRICS/IFIP Performance*, 2024.
- [3] L. **Izhikevich**, M. Tran[†], M. Kallitsis, A. Fass, and Z. Durumeric, "Cloud Watching: Understanding Attacks Against Cloud-Hosted Services", in *Proceedings of the 23rd ACM Internet Measurement Conference*, 2023.
- [4] L. Izhikevich, G. Akiwate, B. Berger[†], S. Drakontaidis[†], A. Ascheman[†], P. Pearce, D. Adrian, and Z. Durumeric, "ZDNS: A Fast DNS Toolkit for Internet Measurement", in *Proceedings of the 22nd ACM Internet Measurement Conference*, *Community Contribution Award*, 2022.
- [5] L. **Izhikevich**, R. Teixeira, and Z. Durumeric, "Predicting IPv4 Services Across All Ports", in *Proceedings of the ACM SIGCOMM Conference*, 2022.
- [6] M. Ziv[†], L. Izhikevich, K. Ruth, K. Izhikevich[†], and Z. Durumeric, "ASdb: A System for Classifying Owners of Autonomous Systems", in *Proceedings of the 21st ACM Internet Measurement Conference*, 2021.
- [7] J. Cable*†, D. Gregory*†, L. **Izhikevich***, and Z. Durumeric, "Stratosphere: Finding Vulnerable Cloud Storage Buckets", in *Proceedings of the 24th International Symposium on Research in Attacks*, *Intrusions and Defenses*, 2021.
- [8] L. Izhikevich, R. Teixeira, and Z. Durumeric, "LZR: Identifying Unexpected Internet Services", in 30th USENIX Security Symposium, 2021.
- [9] G. Wan, L. Izhikevich, D. Adrian, K. Yoshioka, R. Holz, C. Rossow, and Z. Durumeric, "On the Origin of Scanning: The Impact of Location on Internet-Wide Scans", in ACM Internet Measurement Conference, 2020.
- [10] L. Ao, L. **Izhikevich**, G. M. Voelker, and G. Porter, "Sprocket: A Serverless Video Processing Framework", in *Proceedings of the Ninth ACM Symposium on Cloud Computing*, 2018.
- [11] L. **Izhikevich**, E. Peterson, and B. Voytek, "Neural oscillatory power is not Gaussian distributed across time", in *Program No. 271.03. 2016 Neuroscience Meeting Planner*, 2016.

Books

[12] N. Moshiri and L. **Izhikevich**, Design and Analysis of Data Structures. 2016, ISBN: 978-1981017232.

Pre-Prints

- [13] L. **Izhikevich**, R. Teixeira, and Z. Durumeric, "Kronos: A System for Adaptively Tracking Internet Service Dynamics", *Under Submission to SIGCOMM*, 2024.
- [14] L. **Izhikevich**, R. Gao, E. Peterson, and B. Voytek, "Measuring the average power of neural oscillations", bioRxiv, 2018. eprint: https://www.biorxiv.org/content/early/2018/10/13/441626.full.pdf.

Thesis

[15] L. **Izhikevich**, "Building and Breaking Burst-Parallel Systems", M.S. thesis, University of California, San Diego, 2018.

PROFESSIONAL SERVICE

I ROPESSIONAL DERVICE	
Technical Program Committees	
• Internet Measurement Conference	2023-2024
• IEEE Security and Privacy	2023
• Symposium on Research in Attacks, Intrusions, and Defenses	2022-2023
• The Passive and Active Measurement Conference	2022
• IEEE Security and Privacy (External Reviewer)	2022
• USENIX Security (External Reviewer)	2019-2022
• Internet Measurement Conference (External Reviewer)	2019–2021
Department and University Service	
Data Science Faculty Search Committee, Stanford University	2022-2023
• Ethics & Society Review of HAI Seed Grants Committee, Stanford University	2022
• Chair of Ph.D. Applicant Support Program, Stanford University	2021-2023
• Ph.D. Admissions Committee, Computer Science, Stanford University	2019–2022
TEACHING	
• Instructional Assistant at Stanford University	Winter 2022
CS356: Topics in computer Networking and Security, https://cs356.stanford.edu/	
• Co-Creator/Co-Lecturer/Instructional Assistant at Stanford University CS249i: The Modern Internet, https://cs249i.stanford.edu/	Fall 2021
• Instructional Assistant/Discussion Section Leader at UC San Diego CSE100: Advanced Data Structures in C++, assisted 4 times and textbook author	Fall 2015–Winter 2017
• Instructional Assistant/Discussion Section Leader at UC San Diego CSE8B: Introduction to Programming in Java, Part 2	Spring 2017
• Instructional Assistant/Discussion Section Leader at UC San Diego CSE12: Introduction to Data Structures	Fall 2017
• Instructional Assistant/Discussion Section Leader at UC San Diego CSE8A: Introduction to Programming in Java, Part 1	Winter 2018
Mentoring	
(those who have published a peer-reviewed article as part of their independent study)	
• Manda Tran (M.S.)	2021-2023
• Anna Ascheman (B.S)	2022
• Briana Berger (B.S/M.S.)	2021-2022
• Spencer Drakontaidis (B.S.)	2021-2022
• Jack Cable (B.S.)	2020-2021
• Drew Gregory (B.S.)	2020-2021
• Maya Ziv (M.S.)	2020-2021
• Katherine Izhikevich (B.S/M.S.)	2018–Current

REFERENCES

Zakir Durumeric

Assistant Professor of Computer Science Stanford University

Geoffrey Voelker

Professor of Computer Science and Engineering University of California, San Diego

Stefan Savage

Professor of Computer Science and Engineering University of California, San Diego

Renata Cruz Teixeira

Former Director of Research; Current Senior Research Scientist Inria, Paris; Netflix